{
  "name": "Assam after Independence (1947 and Onwards)",
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "Assam became a constituent state of India in the year",
      "options": [
        "A. 1947",
        "B. 1948",
        "C. 1949",
        "D. 1950"
      ],
      "answer": "D. 1950"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who was the first Chief Minister of Assam?",
      "options": [
        "A. Bishnuram Medhi",
        "B. Tarun Ram Phukan",
        "C. Gopinath Bordoloi",
        "D. None of the Above"
      ],
      "answer": "C. Gopinath Bordoloi"
    },
    {
      "question": "After the demise of the 1st Chief Minister of Assam, Gopinath Bordoloi in 1950, the second Chief Minister was",
      "options": [
        "A. B. P. Chaliha",
        "B. R. Medhi",
        "C. Sarat Chandra Singha",
        "D. M. M. Choudhury"
      ],
      "answer": "B. B. R. Medhi"
    },
    {
      "question": "Guwahati University was established in the year",
      "options": [
        "A. 1947",
        "B. 1948",
        "C. 1949",
        "D. 1950"
      ],
      "answer": "B. 1948"
    },
    {
      "question": "The Assam Public Service Commission (APSC) Regulation was promulgated in exercise of the powers in which year?",
      "options": [
        "A. 1947",
        "B. 1950",
        "C. 1951",
        "D. 1960"
      ],
      "answer": "C. 1951"
    },
    {
      "question": "The North-Eastern Frontier Railway (NFR) was set up in the year",
      "options": [
        "A. 1958",
        "B. 1956",
        "C. 1962",
        "D. 1969"
      ],
      "answer": "A. 1958"
    },
    {
      "question": "Assam Language Bill was passed in the year",
      "options": [
        "A. 1940",
        "B. 1950",
        "C. 1960",
        "D. 1970"
      ],
      "answer": "C. 1960"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which state was separated from Assam in 1963?",
      "options": [
        "A. Nagaland",
        "B. Meghalaya",
        "C. Tripura",
        "D. Manipur"
      ],
      "answer": "A. Nagaland"
    },
    {
      "question": "Rani Gaidula, a famous character of the Indian independence movement, belonged to which tribe?",
      "options": [
        "A. The Lalung tribes of Assam",
        "B. The Naga tribes of Assam",
        "C. The Kachari tribes of Assam",
        "D. The Karbi tribes of Assam"
      ],
      "answer": "B. The Naga tribes of Assam"
    },
    {
      "question": "In which year was the All Bodo Students Union (ABSU) formed?",
      "options": [
        "A. 1962",
        "B. 1967",
        "C. 1987",
        "D. 1979"
      ],
      "answer": "B. 1967"
    },
    {
      "question": "When was Mizoram separated from Assam?",
      "options": [
        "A. 1954",
        "B. 1972",
        "C. 1948",
        "D. 1964"
      ],
      "answer": "B. 1972"
    },
    {
      "question": "In which year, the capital of Assam was shifted from Shillong to Dispur?",
      "options": [
        "A. 1950",
        "B. 1955",
        "C. 1971",
        "D. 1973"
      ],
      "answer": "D. 1973"
    },
    {
      "question": "In 1973, the capital of Assam was shifted from Shillong to Dispur. Who was the Chief Minister of Assam at that time?",
      "options": [
        "A. Sarat Chandra Singha",
        "B. Prafulla Mahanta",
        "C. Golap Baruha",
        "D. Bimala Prashad Chaliha"
      ],
      "answer": "A. Sarat Chandra Singha"
    },
    {
      "question": "In which year did the Assam movement start?",
      "options": [
        "A. 1947",
        "B. 1979",
        "C. 1981",
        "D. 1985"
      ],
      "answer": "B. 1979"
    },
    {
      "question": "The antiforeign campaigns were spearheaded by the All Assam Studentsâ€˜ Union, which was led by",
      "options": [
        "A. Prafulla Kumar Mahanta",
        "B. Samujjal Bhattacharya",
        "C. Dipanka Kumar Nath",
        "D. Sankor Jyoti Baruah"
      ],
      "answer": "A. Prafulla Kumar Mahanta"
    },
    {
      "question": "Census work in Assam was not conducted in the year",
      "options": [
        "A. 1971",
        "B. 1981",
        "C. 1991",
        "D. 1961"
      ],
      "answer": "B. 1981"
    },
    {
      "question": "The historic Assam Accord was signed on",
      "options": [
        "A. 15th August, 1985",
        "B. 26th January, 1986",
        "C. 15th August, 1986",
        "D. 15th August, 1990"
      ],
      "answer": "A. 15th August, 1985"
    },
    {
      "question": "A committee to implement clause 6 of the Assam Accord was led by",
      "options": [
        "A. Justice BK Sarma",
        "B. Justice Ranjan Gogoi",
        "C. Justice PK Goswami",
        "D. Justice Madan B Lokur"
      ],
      "answer": "A. Justice BK Sarma"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which party came to power in Assam in 1985?",
      "options": [
        "A. Janata",
        "B. Asom Gana Parishad",
        "C. Dravida Munnetra Kazhagam",
        "D. Congress"
      ],
      "answer": "B. Asom Gana Parishad"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following cultural institutions was born as a result of the Assam Accord?",
      "options": [
        "A. Rock Garden",
        "B. Assam State Museum",
        "C. Rabindra Bhawan",
        "D. Srimanta Sankardev Kalakshetra"
      ],
      "answer": "D. Srimanta Sankardev Kalakshetra"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which refinery was established due to the 'Assam accord'?",
      "options": [
        "A. Guwahati",
        "B. Bongaigaon",
        "C. Numaligarh",
        "D. Digboi"
      ],
      "answer": "C. Numaligarh"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who was the Prime Minister of India at the time of signing the Assam Accord?",
      "options": [
        "A. Indira Gandhi",
        "B. Deve Gowda",
        "C. AB Vajpayee",
        "D. Rajiv Gandhi"
      ],
      "answer": "D. Rajiv Gandhi"
    }
  ]
}
